A dream to save the wilderness. A secret that shocked the world.
Grey Owl is a western, action, drama film directed by Richard Attenborough.
Archie Grey Owl is a trapper in Canada in the early 1930s when a young
Iroquois woman from town asks him to teach her Indian ways.
They live in the woods, where she is appalled at how trapped animals die.
She adopts two orphaned beaver kits and helps
Archie see his way to stop trapping.
Instead, he works as a guide, a naturalist writer, and then the Canadian government hires him to
save the beaver in a conserve by Lake Ajawaan in Prince Albert National Park.
He writes a biography, which brings him attention in
Canada and invitations to lecture in England.
Before he leaves, he and Anahareo (Pony) marry.
In England, his secret is revealed.
Will Anahareo continue to love him?
Grey Owl, played by Pierce Brosnan.
Cyrus Finney, played by Stewart Bick.
Harry Champlin, played by Vlasta Vrana.
Pony, played by Annie Galipeau.
First Hunter, played by Neil Kroetsch.
Second Hunter, played by Serge Houde.
Grey Owl is a 1999 biographical film directed by Richard Attenborough and starring Pierce Brosnan in the role of real-life British schoolboy turned Native
American trapper "Grey Owl", Archibald Belaney (1888–1938), and Annie Galipeau as his wife Anahareo, with brief appearances by Graham Greene and others.
The screenplay was written by William Nicholson.
The film was released on 10 September 1999 in Spain and 15 February 2000 in US.
It was the last film made by Largo Entertainment before it went defunct in 1999.
The tone is emotional.